Guide to the J. B. Matthews Papers, 1862-1986 and undated
J. B. Matthews papers 1862-1986 and undated
- Vertical Files Series, ca. 1920s-1980s Part V
  - New York Committee for the General Strike for Peace Provisional Committee, 1962-1963 (Folder 19)
  - New York Committee for the Protection of Foreign Born, 1955 (Folder 20)
  - New York Committee for the Struggle Against War, undated (Folder 21)
  - New York Committee for Withdrawal Referendum, 1967 (Folder 22)
  - New York Committee to Aid the Maryland Freedom Union, 1966 (Folder 23)
  - New York Committee to End the War in Vietnam (SDS), 1965 (Folder 24)
  - New York Committee to Win the Peace, 1946-1947& undated (Folder 25)
  - New York Communist Party, 1961 (Folder 26)
  - New York Conference for Inalienable Rights, 1940-1942& undated (Folder 27)
  - New York Conference to Repeal the Walter-McCarran Law and Defend its Victims, 1954 (Folder 28)
  - New York Council for a Permanent FEPC, 1941 (Folder 29)
  - New York Council of Performing Artists, 1964 (Folder 30)
  - New York Council to Abolish the House Un-American Activities Committee, 1960-1965 (Folder 31-32)
  - New York County Communist Party, 1948-1949 (Folder 33)
  - New York Draft and Military Law Panel, 1968-1969 (Folder 34)
  - New York DuBois Clubs, undated (Box 436, Folder 1)
  - New York Elections, 1949 (Folder 2)
  - The New York Element, 1970 (Folder 3)
  - The New York Express, 1970 (Folder 4)
  - New York Federation of College Teachers, 1942 (Folder 5)
  - New York Free Press, 1968 (Folder 6)
  - The New York G. I. Coffee House Project, 1969-1970 (Folder 7)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1946, 1951 (Folder 8)
  - New York High School Free Press, 1969 (Folder 9)
  - New York Interracial Singers, undated (Folder 10)
  - New York Jewish Peoples Committee Against Fascism and AntiSemitism, undated (Folder 11)
  - New York Joint Action Committee for Genuine Social Insurance, 1935-1936 (Folder 12)
  - New York Labor Committee for Wallace and Taylor, 1946& undated (Folder 13)
  - New York Labor Conference for Peace, 1950-1953& undated (Folder 14-15)
  - New York Labor War Chest, 1943 (Folder 16)
  - New York Medical Committee to End the War in Vietnam, 1967-1968 (Folder 17)
  - New York Newspaper Guild, 1955 (Folder 18)
  - New York Peace Action Coalition, 1971 (Folder 19)
  - New York Peace Association, 1971 (Folder 20)
  - New York Peace Information Center, 1964 (Folder 21)
  - New York Peace Institute, 1952 (Folder 22)
  - New York Poets for Peace, 1966-1967 (Folder 23)
  - New York Post, 1934 (Folder 24)
  - New York Professional Workers Conference on Social Insurance, 1934 (Folder 25)
  - New York Provo, 1967 (Folder 26)
  - New York Review of Books, 1968 (Folder 27)
  - New York School of Marxist Studies, 1961-1967 (Folder 28)
  - New York Society of Clinical Psychologists, Inc., 1968 (Folder 29)
  - New York State American Federation of Labor Committee for the Election of Labor Party Candidates, 1938 (Folder 30)
  - New York State Council, 1945 (Folder 31)
  - New York State Civil Rights Congress, 1949-1951& undated (Box 437, Folder 1)
  - The New York State Committee on Discrimination in Housing, 1949 (Folder 2)
  - New York State Conference on National Unity, undated (Folder 3)
  - New York State Conference on Negro Youth, 1944 (Folder 4)
  - New York State Council for Legislative Action, 1949 (Folder 5)
  - New York State Council of the Arts, Sciences, and Professions, 1949-1951& undated (Folder 6)
  - New York State Educators for Wallace, undated (Folder 7)
  - New York State Optometrists Against the War in Vietnam, 1968 (Folder 8)
  - New York Sunday Report, 1945 (Folder 9)
  - New York Teacher News
    - Papers, 1949-1959 (Folder 10-13)
    - Papers, 1960-1964 (Box 438, Folder 1-4)
  - New York Teachers Guild, 1948 (Folder 5)
  - New York Tenant Councils on Rent and Housing, 1948 (Folder 6)
  - The New York Times, 1957-1970& undated (Folder 7)
  - New York-Tome Mooney Congress Committee, undated (Folder 8)
  - New York Trade Union Committee to Free Earl Browder, 1942& undated (Folder 9)
  - New York Trade Union Solidarity Committee for the Hazard Miners, 1963-1964 (Folder 10)
  - New York University, 1949-1970& undated (Folder 11)
  - New York University Committee to End the War in Vietnam, 1967-1968 (Folder 12)
  - New York Urban Coalition, 1968-1969 (Folder 13)
  - New York Women's Trade Union League, undated (Box 439, Folder 1)
  - New York Workers School, 1943 (Folder 2)
  - New York Workshop in Violence, 1965-1968, undated (Folder 3)
  - New York Youth Council, 1946-1948& undated (Folder 4)
  - New Yorkers for the Constitution, 1967& undated (Folder 5)
  - Newark Community Union Project, 1968 (Folder 6)
  - Newfield, Jack, 1969 (Folder 7)
  - News, 1951-1955 (Folder 8)
  - News & Letters, 1963-1967 (Folder 9)
  - News for Action, 1958-1960 (Folder 10)
  - News Letter
    - Papers, 1939-1941,Mar. (Folder 11-13)
    - Papers, 1941, Apr.-Dec. (Box 440, Folder 1)
  - Newsletter from Behind the Iron Curtain (Folder 2)
  - Newsletter on Intellectual Freedom, 1952-1956 (Folder 3)
  - Newsman's Gadfly, 1964-1965 (Folder 4)
  - Newsmen's Commission to Investigate the Murder of George Polk, 1948 (Folder 5)
  - Newspapers Guild of New York, 1950, 1969& undated (Folder 6)
  - The Newsreel, 1968-1970 (Folder 7)
  - Newsweek, 1946-1950& undated (Folder 8)
  - The Newton-Cleaver Defense Committee, 1968-1969 (Folder 9)
  - Nickel Review, 1970 (Folder 10)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1953 (Folder 11)
  - Nimitz Commission, 1951 (Folder 12)
  - The 1976 Committee, 1967 (Folder 13)
  - (1960) Campaign for Disarmament, 1960 (Folder 14)
  - 1960 Labor and People's Committee for May Day, 1960 (Folder 15)
  - 1968 and 1969 Trends and Development, 1968-1969 (Folder 16)
  - The 1967 Committee to End the Draft, 1965 (Folder 17)
  - 1962 Union Square May Day Committee, 1962 (Folder 18)
  - Ninth Street Neighbors for Peace, 1968 (Folder 19)
  - Nixon, Richard, 1960-1969 (Folder 20)
  - No Amnesty for Deserters, 1969 (Folder 21)
  - No More Miss America, 1968 (Folder 22)
  - No More War, 1967 (Folder 23)
  - No Tax for War in Vietnam Committee, 1965-1968 (Folder 24)
  - Nok Vilaga, 1958 (Folder 25)
  - Non-Commercial Educational Broadcasting Station of Fordham University, 1948 (Folder 26)
  - Noncooperation with Conscription, 1967& undated (Folder 27)
  - Non-partisan Citizen Committee for the Election of Paul P. Rao, 1941 (Folder 28)
  - Non-partisan Committee for the Defense of Fred E. Beal, 1938, 1962 (Folder 29)
  - Non-partisan Committee for the Re-election of Vito Marcantonio, 1936 (Folder 30)
  - Non-partisan Youth Committee, 1939 (Folder 31)
  - Non-sectarian Anti-Nazi League to Champion Human Rights, Inc., 1940-1955& undated (Box 441, Folder 1)
  - Non-sectarian Committee for German Refugee Children, 1939 (Folder 2)
  - Non-sectarian Committee for Political Refugees, 1960& undated (Folder 3)
  - Non-violent Action Against Nuclear Weapons, 1957 (Folder 4)
  - Non-violent Caucus, 1968 (Folder 5)
  - Non-violent Committee for Cuban Independence, 1961 (Folder 6)
  - Non-violent Direct Action Committee, 1967 (Folder 7)
  - Non-violent Training and Action Center, 1969 (Folder 8)
  - Noontide Press, 1957, 1962 (Folder 9)
  - Norman, E. Herbert, 1957 (Folder 10)
  - The Norman Tallentire Defense Committee, 1952 (Folder 11)
  - The Norman Thomas Fund, 1936, 1969& undated (Folder 12)
  - North, Alex, 1954 (Folder 13)
  - North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy, 1936-1969& undated (Folder 14)
  - North American Congress on Latin America, 1967-1969 (Folder 15)
  - The North American Friends of Cuba, undated (Folder 16)
  - North American Labor, 1948 (Folder 17)
  - North American Spanish Aid Committee, 1940& undated (Folder 18)
  - North American Student Cooperative League, 1957 (Folder 19)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization, 1949, 1955 (Folder 20)
  - North Dade Citizen's Guide, 1960 (Folder 21)
  - North Park Community Peace Center, 1965 (Folder 22)
  - North Shore Community Arts Center, 1959 (Folder 23)
  - North Shore Women for Peace, 1962, 1965 (Folder 24)
  - North Side Cooperative Ministry, 1967 (Folder 25)
  - North Side Organizing Committee for a New Marxist Leninist Youth Organization, 1970 (Folder 26)
  - North Ward Citizens Committee, 1968 (Folder 27)
  - Northeastern Union Farmer, 1955-1958 (Folder 28)
  - Northern Book House, 1957-1965& undated (Box 442, Folder 1)
  - Northern California Committee for Abolition of Nuclear Tests, 1957-1959 (Folder 2)
  - Northern California Peace Council, 1955-1956 (Folder 3)
  - Northern California Teachers Defense Committee, 1959-1961 (Folder 4)
  - Northern Illinois Citizens Against the ABM, 1969 (Folder 5)
  - Northern Illinois University, 1968-1969 (Folder 6)
  - Northern Neighbours, 1956-1968 (Folder 7)
  - Northern New Mexico Support Committee, 1969 (Folder 8)
  - Northern New York Committee for Alternatives in Vietnam, 1967 (Folder 9)
  - Northwest Youth Festival Committee, 1959 (Folder 10)
  - Northwestern University, 1948-1969& undated (Folder 11)
  - Notes from Cuba, 1969 (Folder 12)
  - Nova Doba, 1944- New Era (Folder 13)
  - Novel Press, 1969 (Folder 14)
  - November 8th Movement, 1969 (Folder 15)
  - Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, 1968 (Folder 16)
  - Nowak, Stanley, 1954 (Folder 17)
  - Nowy Swiat, 1945 (Folder 18)
  - Nuclear Energy Research Bureau, 1956 (Folder 19)
  - Nuclear Policy Letter Committee, 1962 (Folder 20)
  - La Nueva Voz, 1963-1969 (Folder 21)
  - Oak Publications, Inc., 1964-1969 (Box 443, Folder 1)
  - Oakland Direct Action Committee, 1967-1968 (Folder 2)
  - Oakland Peace/Freedom Center, 1967 (Folder 3)
  - Obituaries, 1970-1971 (Folder 4)
  - The Obligore, 1969-1970 (Folder 5)
  - O'Brien, Lawrence, 1970 (Folder 6)
  - O'Casey, Sean, undated (Folder 7)
  - Ocean-Hill Brownsvillee, 1968-1969 (Folder 8)
  - Oceana Publications, Inc., 1949-1964& undated (Folder 9)
  - O'Dwyer, Paul, 1968-1969 (Folder 10)
  - Off Our Backs, 1970 (Folder 11)
  - Office for Intellectual Freedom, 1969 (Folder 12)
  - Office of Defense Mobilization, 1951 (Folder 13)
  - Office of Price Administration, 1941-1943 (Folder 14)
  - Office of Special Investigation (OSI) U.S.A. Intelligence, 1951& undated (Folder 15)
  - Office of Strategic Services, 1943-1960 (Folder 16)
  - Office of War Information, 1942, 1944 (Folder 17)
  - Office Work, undated (Folder 18)
  - Office Worker, 1935 (Folder 19)
  - The Officer, 1970 (Folder 20)
  - Oglesby, Carl, 1970 (Folder 21)
  - Ohio, undated (Folder 22)
  - Ohio Bill of Rights Conference, 1956 (Folder 23)
  - The Ohio Coalition, 1948-1950 (Folder 24)
  - Ohio Committee for Smith Act Defendants, 1955-1956& undated (Folder 25)
  - Ohio Labor Conference for Peace, 1959 (Folder 26)
  - Ohio State University, 1965-1968 (Folder 27)
  - Ohio State University Committee to End the War in Vietnam, 1967 (Folder 28)
  - Ohioans for a Reasonable Settlement in Vietnam, 1966-1967 (Box 444, Folder 1)
  - Oil Workers International Union, undated (Folder 2)
  - Olatunji Center of African Culture, 1958 (Folder 3)
  - Olds, Leland S., 1949 (Folder 4)
  - Olympic Games, 1968 (Folder 5)
  - OM. the Liberation Newsletter, 1969 (Folder 6)
  - On Guard Committee for Freedom, 1961-1962 (Folder 7)
  - Onassis, A. S., 1955-1956 (Folder 8)
  - One, 1959 (Folder 9)
  - One Magazine, 1953-1955 (Folder 10)
  - One World, 1967 (Folder 11)
  - Ontario Young New Democrats, 1969 (Folder 12)
  - The Open Forum of Maryland, 1962-1964 (Folder 13)
  - Open Letter for Closer Cooperation with the Soviet Union, 1939 (Folder 14)
  - Open Letter for Ending the War and Making Peace in South Vietnam, 1963 (Folder 15)
  - Open Letter Protesting Ban on Communists in the American Civil Liberties Union, 1940 (Folder 16)
  - Open Letter to American Liberals, 1937 (Folder 17)
  - Open Letter to J. Howard McGrath, 1951 (Folder 18)
  - Open Letter to President John F. Kennedy for Ending the War and Making Peace in South Vietnam, 1963 (Folder 19)
  - Open Letter to President Roosevelt for Harry Bridges, 1943 (Folder 20)
  - The Open Press, 1967-1968 (Folder 21)
  - Open Sights, 1969 (Folder 22)
  - Operation Abolition, 1961 (Folder 23)
  - Operation Alert, 1970 (Folder 24)
  - Operation Crossroads Africa, Inc., 1964-1966 (Folder 25)
  - Operation Dixie, 1946 (Folder 26)
  - Operation Freedom, 1964-1968 (Folder 27)
  - Operation Get McCarthy, 1952-1954& undated (Folder 28)
  - Operation Open Debate, 1967 (Box 445, Folder 1)
  - Operation Subsistence, 1947-1948& undated (Folder 2)
  - Operation Water Moccasin, 1964 (Folder 3)
  - Operation Women, 1934-1952 (Folder 4)
  - Operation X, 1952-1953& undated (Folder 5)
  - Opinion Research Corporation, 1954 (Folder 6)
  - Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1950-1969& undated (Folder 7)
  - Opposition, 1964 (Folder 8)
  - Orange County Committee to End the War in Vietnam, 1967 (Folder 9)
  - Order of Formal Russian Military, Inc., 1959 (Folder 10)
  - Oregon Ad Hoc Committee to Abolish the H.U.A.C., 1964 (Folder 11)
  - Oregon Commonwealth Federation, 1937 (Folder 12)
  - Organization for Black Power, 1965-1968 (Folder 13)
  - Organization for Revolutionary Action, 1968 (Folder 14)
  - Organization of African Students, 1968 (Folder 15)
  - Organization of Afro-American Unity, 1964-1969& undated (Folder 16)
  - Organization of Arab Students, 1969 (Folder 17)
  - Organizers, 1968 (Folder 18)
  - Organizing Brooklyn for Wallace, 1949 (Box 446, Folder 1)
  - Organizing Committee to Bring Troops Home Now, 1966 (Folder 2)
  - Osman, Arthur, 1945-1951& undated (Folder 3)
  - Osth, Betsy, 1969 (Folder 4)
  - Osth Information Service, 1969-1970 (Folder 5)
  - Oswald, Lee Harvey, 1963-1969 (Folder 6-7)
  - Otepka, Otto, 1966-1969 (Folder 8)
  - Othello Recording Corporation, 1952 (Folder 9)
  - Other Americans, 1963-1964 (Folder 10)
  - Other Scenes, 1968 (Folder 11)
  - The Other Side, 1964 (Folder 12)
  - Otten Testimonial Dinner, undated (Folder 13)
  - Ottenheimer, Albert, undated (Folder 14)
  - Our America, 1933 (Box 447, Folder 1)
  - Our Country, 1963-1975& undated (Folder 2)
  - Our Generation, 1969-1970 (Folder 3)
  - Out Voltaire!, 1955 (Folder 4)
  - Overseas Press Club Bulletin, 1952 (Folder 5)
  - Overseas Vietnamese Buddhist Association, 1967 (Folder 6)
  - Overseas Weekly, 1967 (Folder 7)
  - Oxnam, G. Broxnley, 1931-1958& undated (Folder 8)
  - PM, 1941-1947 (Box 448, Folder 1)
  - P.R. Club, C.P., 1946 (Folder 2)
  - Pacific Northwest Labor School, 1947 (Folder 3)
  - Pacific School of Religion of Berkeley California, undated (Folder 4)
  - Pacific Weekly, 1935 (Folder 5)
  - Pacifica Foundation, 1960-1969 (Folder 6)
  - Pacifist Movement, 1927-1942, undated (Folder 7)
  - Packer, Herbert L., 1966 (Folder 8)
  - Packinghouse Workers, 1970 (Folder 9)
  - Paffrath, Leslie, 1964 (Folder 10)
  - Pakistani Muslims, 1966 (Folder 11)
  - Palestine Liberation Organization, 1969 (Folder 12)
  - Palestine Resistance Fund, 1947 (Folder 13)
  - Paley, Jack, 1953(?) (Folder 14)
  - Palo Alto Peace Club, 1951-1966 (Folder 15)
  - Pan American Women's Association, 1969& undated (Folder 16)
  - Panther Publications Inc., 1966, 1968 (Folder 17)
  - Paperbox Makers Union, 1947 (Folder 18)
  - Papers on Appeal, 1945 (Folder 19)
  - Parcels to Russia, 1957& undated (Folder 20)
  - Parents Committee to Safeguard Children from War Tensions in the Schools, 1950 (Folder 21)
  - Parents for Responsibility in Toy Industry, 1966 (Folder 22)
  - Parlin, Charles, 1954 (Folder 23)
  - Parochial School Defender, undated (Folder 24)
  - The Partisan, 1965-1968 (Folder 25)
  - Partisan Republicans of California, 1949 (Folder 26)
  - Partisan Review, 1946-1958 (Folder 27)
  - Partisan Review & Anvil, 1936 (Box 449, Folder 1)
  - Party Educator, 1939 (Folder 2)
  - Party News, 1940 (Folder 3)
  - Party Voice, 1955-1956 (Folder 4)
  - Pasadena Affair, 1950-1951 (Folder 5)
  - Pasadena Non-Partisan Committee for Peace, 1953 (Folder 6)
  - Pasadena Peace Committee, 1953 (Folder 7)
  - Pathways to Peace, 1963 (Folder 8)
  - Patra Travel Agency, 1959 (Folder 9)
  - Patriot Party, undated (Folder 10)
  - Patriotic Citizenship Association, 1952 (Folder 11)
  - Patterson, Frederick, 1956 (Folder 12)
  - Patterson, William, 1967 (Folder 13)
  - Patton, Guy, 1950 (Folder 14)
  - Paul Brown Defense Committee, 1956 (Folder 15)
  - Paul Revere Associated Yeomen, 1965-1968 (Folder 16)
  - Paul Robeson at Canadian Border, 1936, 1952& undated (Folder 17)
  - Pauling, Linus, 1947-1967& undated (Folder 18-19)
  - Pauling Party Committee, 1960 (Folder 20)
  - The Pawn, 1969 (Folder 21)
  - Pax Et Progressus, 1959 (Folder 22)
  - Peace, 1950, 1961, 1968 (Folder 23)
  - Peace Action, 1958 (Folder 24)
  - Peace Action Calendar, 1962 (Folder 25)
  - Peace Action Center, 1961-1969 (Box 450, Folder 1-2)
  - Peace Action Committee, 1967-1968 (Folder 3)
  - Peace Action Council, 1966-1969& undated (Folder 4)
  - Peace Action Symbol, 1958 (Folder 5)
  - Peace Activists Defense Committee, 1966 (Folder 6)
  - Peace Aids, undated (Folder 7)
  - Peace and Equal Rights Committee, 1969 (Folder 8)
  - Peace and Freedom Club Chairmen, 1968 (Folder 9)
  - Peace and Freedom Movement, 1967 (Folder 10)
  - Peace and Freedom News, 1968 (Folder 11)
  - Peace and Freedom Party
    - Papers, 1967-1968,July (Folder 12)
    - Papers, 1968, Aug.-1969& undated (Box 451, Folder 1)
  - Peace Book Company, 1964-1968& undated (Folder 2)
  - Peace Festival Committee, 1952 (Folder 3)
  - Peace Information, 1950-1964& undated (Folder 4)
  - Peace-Keeping Ways and Means Committee, 1966 (Folder 5)
  - Peace News, 1956-1958 (Folder 6)
  - Peace Newsletter, 1961 (Folder 7)
  - Peace New Movement, 1944 (Folder 8)
  - Peace Pamphletters, 1944, 1948 (Folder 9)
  - Peace Patriots, 1929& undated (Folder 10)
  - Peace Plebiscite, 1935 (Folder 11)
  - Peace Products, 1969 (Folder 12)
  - Peace Publication Fund, 1949-1964 (Folder 13)
  - Peace Research Center, 1970 (Folder 14)
  - Peace Review, 1954 (Folder 15)
  - Peace Rights Organizing Committee, 1966 (Folder 16)
  - Peace Study Institute, 1958 (Folder 17)
  - Peace Torch, 1967 (Folder 18)
  - Peace Union, 1964 (Folder 19)
  - Peace Will Win, 1952& undated (Folder 20)
  - Peaceful Coexistence, 1959-1961& undated (Folder 21)
  - The Peacemaker, 1951-1971& undated (Box 452, Folder 1-3)
  - Pearson, Andrew "Drew" Russell, 1936-1969 (Folder 4-5)
  - Pearson Suit, 1914-1956& undated (Box 453, Folder 1)
  - Pearson's Magazine, 1918-1923 (Folder 2-3)
  - Peekskill Demonstration, 1949-1969& undated (Folder 4-5)
  - Peekskill Violence, 1949-1950& undated (Folder 6)
  - Peet, Edward, 1961 (Folder 7)
  - Pegasus, 1968 (Folder 8)
  - Peggy Wellman Case, 1954 (Folder 9)
  - Pegler, Westbrook, 1942-1952 (Folder 10)
  - Pelley, William Dudley, 1950 (Folder 11)
  - Peninsula Committee for Freedom in Education, 1959 (Folder 12)
  - Penkovsky, Oleg Vladimirovich, 1965-1966 (Folder 13)
  - Pennsylvania Civil Rights Congress, 1955 (Box 454, Folder 1)
  - Pennsylvania Committee to Defend the Pittsburgh Six, 1952 (Folder 2)
  - Pennsylvania Congress for American Liberties, undated (Folder 3)
  - Pennsylvania Right to Work Defense and Education Foundation, undated (Folder 4)
  - Pent-it Books, Inc., 1969 (Folder 5)
  - People Against Racism, 1968-1969 (Folder 6)
  - People for Peace, 1962-1967 (Folder 7)
  - People to Abolish Abortion Laws, 1970 (Folder 8)
  - People Today, 1952 (Folder 9)
  - People's Artists, Inc., 1946-1960& undated (Folder 10-11)
  - People's Centennial Book Committee, 1958 (Folder 12)
  - People's China, 1950-1956 (Folder 13)
  - People's College, 1916 (Folder 14)
  - People's Committee for Freedom of Religion, undated (Folder 15)
  - People's Committee for Mental Hygiene, 1946 (Folder 16)
  - People's Conference to Repeal the McCarran Act, 1954 (Folder 17)
  - People's Constitutional Party, 1968 (Folder 18)
  - The People's Council of America, 1917-1918 (Folder 19)
  - People's Culture Union of America, 1947 (Folder 20)
  - People's Daily World, 1946-1969& undated (Folder 21)
  - People's Defense Union, 1965 (Folder 22)
  - People's Drama, Inc. 1949-1950& undated (Folder 23)
  - People's Education Center, 1945-1947 (Folder 24)
  - People's Freedom Movement, 1956-1957 (Folder 25)
  - People's Front for Peace, 1937 (Box 455, Folder 1)
  - People's Fund, 1972-1974& undated (Folder 2)
  - People's Institute of Applied Religion, 1941-1948 (Folder 3)
  - People's League for Germandom Abroad, undated (Folder 4)
  - The People's Lobby, Inc., 1933, 1949& undated (Folder 5)
  - People's Mandate to Government, undated (Folder 6)
  - People's Party-State of Washington, 1948 (Folder 7)
  - People's Peace, 1947, 1961 (Folder 8)
  - People's Peace Treaty, 1971 (Folder 9)
  - People's Press, 1933-1937 (Folder 10)
  - People's Poverty Board, 1967 (Folder 11)
  - People's Progress State, 1967 (Folder 12)
  - People's Radio Foundation, 1944-1947& undated (Folder 13)
  - People's Rights Party, 1946-1964 (Folder 14)
  - People's Songs, Inc., 1946-1963& undated (Folder 15)
  - Pezzati, Albert, 1938-1952 (Folder 16)
  - Phillips, Robert, 1961-1964 (Folder 17)
  - Piastro, Mishel, 1946 (Folder 18)
  - Picasso, Pablo, 1957 (Box 456, Folder 1)
  - Pickett, Clarence, undated (Folder 2)
  - Piegdon, Walter, undated (Folder 3)
  - Pike, H. Harvey Jr., 1946 (Folder 4)
  - Pines, Don, 1946 (Folder 5)
  - Pious, Minerva, 1950& undated (Folder 6)
  - Pipe, William L., 1942 (Folder 7)
  - Pirinsky, George, 1945 (Folder 8)
  - Pitkin, Wolcott H., 1946 (Folder 9)
  - Pittman, Hobson, 1951 (Folder 10)
  - Pizer, Morris, undated (Folder 11)
  - The Plain Truth, 1969 (Folder 12)
  - Planned Communities, Inc., 1961 (Folder 13)
  - Planned Economy, 1949 (Folder 14)
  - Planned Parenthood-World Population, 1970 (Folder 15)
  - Platform. 1946, 1949 (Folder 16)
  - Platrick, Sophia, 1947 (Folder 17)
  - Plotnik, Harry, 1949 (Folder 18)
  - The Plough Publishing House, 1964 (Folder 19)
  - Podell, Bertram, undated (Folder 20)
  - Poetry, 1938 (Folder 21)
  - Polan, Lou, 1955 (Folder 22)
  - Poland, 1961, 1965 (Folder 23)
  - Poland of Today, 1949 (Folder 24)
  - Poland Today, 1950 (Folder 25)
  - Police Brutality, 1968 (Folder 26)
  - Polier, Justine Wise, ca. 1948-1953 (Folder 27)
  - Polish-American Congress, Inc., 1946 (Folder 28)
  - Polish Embassy, 1950 (Folder 29)
  - Polish News, 1962 (Folder 30)
  - Polish Organizations (Anti-Communist), 1945 (Folder 31)
  - Polish Perspectives, 1962 (Folder 32)
  - Polish Research and Information Service, 1949 (Folder 33)
  - Political Action Committee, 1944-1946 (Folder 34)
  - Political Action Committee for Palestine, Inc., 1947 (Folder 35)
  - Political Action Committee of the Jefferson Student Council, 1947 (Folder 36)
  - Political Affairs, 1945-1970 (Box 457, Folder 1)
  - Political Affairs Club, 1967 (Folder 2)
  - Political Affairs Forum, 1967 (Folder 3)
  - Political Affairs Publishers, Inc., 1964 (Folder 4)
  - Political Alliance for Peace and Human Progress, 1967 (Folder 5)
  - Political Prisoners Bail Fund Committee, 1935 (Folder 6)
  - The Political Yearbook, 1951 (Folder 7)
  - Politics for Peace, 1967 (Folder 8)
  - Polk, George, 1948-1949 (Folder 9)
  - Pollock, Ernest, 1947 (Folder 10)
  - Pomona College, 1968 (Folder 11)
  - Pontecorvo, Bruno, 1950, 1960 (Folder 12)
  - Poor People's Campaign, 1937, 1938 (Folder 13)
  - Poor People's Corporation, 1966-1967 (Folder 14)
  - Pope, Liston, 1955 (Folder 15)
  - Porter, Charles, 1956 (Folder 16)
  - Porter, Ellis, 1969 (Folder 17)
  - Porter Sargent Publisher, 1968 (Folder 18)
  - Porter, Sylvia, 1955 (Folder 19)
  - Portland Committee to End the War in Viet Nam, 1966 (Folder 20)
  - Portland Draft Resister's Union, 1967 (Folder 21)
  - Portland State College, 1967 (Folder 22)
  - Port-Light, 1959 (Folder 23)
  - Portuguese-American Committee for Democracy, 1945 (Folder 24)